(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Que Sera Sora!
せーの、ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Ready, go! Que Sera Sora!
「ケ・セラ・ソラ！」 作詞・作曲：komo(猫多)
"Que Sera Sora!" Lyrics/Composition: komo (Nekota)
皆さん、今日はときのそら６周年突破記念に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you for coming today to Tokino Sora's 6th anniversary celebration!
おはよう　配信　今日もご挨拶
Good morning! Streaming and greeting you again today.
てあれ、嘘、もうこんな時間？
Wait, no way, is it already this time?
午後から予定あるのに
I have plans this afternoon,
すぐに支度をしなきゃ
so I've gotta get ready right away!
いってきます！
I'm heading out!
慌てず飛び出して気づく
Rushing out and realizing...
こっちじゃない　ここどこ？
This isn't the right way, where am I?
助けて、あん肝！
Help me, Ankimo!
トラブルばっか　転んで起きての
It's nothing but trouble, falling down and getting up,
毎日です
every single day.
何でも思い通りとか
Things going exactly as planned...
そんなおいしい話はないけど
There's no such sweet deal,
心の曇り空を晴らす
but if I say the magic words
合言葉　唱えたらで
to clear the cloudy skies in my heart...
ほら　快晴でしょ
Look, the sky's clear now!
ずっと　みんなに届けたい
I want to keep sending to everyone...
歌もダンスも元気も
Songs, dances, and energy!
きっと　同じ空の下
Surely, under the same sky,
笑顔も分け合えるよ
we can share our smiles.
ちょっと　疲れちゃう時も
Even when I'm a little tired,
涙零れそうな時も
even when tears are about to fall...
いつもの魔法の言葉今日も
Today too, I'll say those magic words...
ケセラセラなそら
Que sera sera Sora!
せーの、ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Ready, go! Que Sera Sora!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
こんそめ！ 今日も一日頑張ろう
Kon-some! Let's do our best today too.
カメラにマイクに
Camera, microphone...
よし　準備OK
Alright, I'm all set!
お水もちゃんとあるし
I've got my water ready,
備えさえあれば嬉しいです
and with everything ready, I'm happy.
それじゃ　今日は何をしようかな
Well then, what should I do today?
お歌に雑談に
Singing, chatting...
あ、ホラ、コラボ！
Oh, look, a collaboration!
みんなと笑い飛ばせば
If we laugh it off with everyone,
また明日は晴ればれだ
tomorrow will be bright and sunny again.
よっしゃ！
Alright!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ギター！村山遼さん！
Guitar! Ryo Murayama!
ほっと　ため息零して
Letting out a sigh of relief,
ふと夜空を見上げたら
I happened to look up at the night sky,
ぱっと　満天の星たちが
and suddenly, a sky full of stars
キラキラ瞬いてた
were twinkling brilliantly.
ずっと　追いかけ続けたい
I want to keep chasing them forever,
雲より高い夢でも
even if it's a dream higher than the clouds.
もっと　強く羽ばたいて
I'll flap my wings even harder
空まで駆けてゆくよ
and soar all the way to the sky!
そっと　背中を押すような
If I'm wrapped in a warmth
温もりに包まれたら
that gently pushes me forward,
いつまでも止まらないよ今日も
today too, I'll never stop.
明日も
Tomorrow too,
ずっと
Forever,
ケセラセラなそら
Que sera sera Sora!
せーの、ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Ready, go! Que Sera Sora!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
はい、というわけで...
Alright, so...
みなさん、見えてる？
Can everyone see me?
聞こえてる？声、聞こえてますか？
Can you hear me? Is my voice coming through?
初めまして、みなさんときのそらです。
Nice to meet you all, I'm Tokino Sora.
本日はここで路上ライブをやらせていただけるということで、とても嬉しく思っています。
I'm very happy to be able to perform a street live here today.
ギターの村山遼さんに来ていただいて...
I've invited guitarist Murayama Reo to join me...
一緒に路上でライブをしていきたいなと思っております。
...and we'll be performing this street live together.
よろしくお願いします。
I hope you enjoy it.
いやあ、みなさん聞こえてますか？ありがとうございます。
Wow, can you all hear me? Thank you very much.
初めてのアコースティックのライブでちょっと緊張してるんですけども、
It's my first acoustic live, so I'm a bit nervous,
一生懸命1時間頑張りますので、よろしくお願いします。
but I'll do my best for the next hour, so please support me.
次の曲も元気な曲を選びました。
I've chosen another energetic song for the next one.
聴いてください。ピッと！して！マーマレード。
Please listen: 'Pit-to! Shite! Marmalade.'
こんなに こんなに 叶えたいんだ
This much, this much, I want to make it come true
強く願って 願うだけ 夢になった
Just by wishing, wishing strongly, it became a dream
そうだから しっかり ピッと！して！マーマレード
That's why, firmly, Pit-to! Shite! Marmalade
私頑張るよ 頑張るからね
I'll do my best, I'll really do my best
よっしゃ、ゲット、セット、レディ、ゴー！
Alright, get set, ready, go!
ピッと！して！マーマレード
Pit-to! Shite! Marmalade
作詞・作曲：田淵智也
Lyrics/Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
時に満面で 時に茶化して
Sometimes with a big smile, sometimes joking around
時に凛々しく
Sometimes dignified
コロコロ変わる 空模様みたい
Changing rapidly, like the sky's pattern
どれもちゃーんと そらだし
Every one of them is truly Sora
繋ぐ星と星のフレーズ 私と君の
Connecting the phrases of star to star, between you and me
やり取りが線になる
Our interactions become a line
素敵ロマンチックで ドラマチック
Wonderful romantic and dramatic
星座になって そして歌になる
Becoming a constellation and then becoming a song
日進月歩と言えるほど 逞しく
Robustly enough to be called steady progress
できてないかもしれない
Maybe I haven't quite managed it yet
精々トライアンドエラーって感じか
At best, it feels like trial and error
ハイメイミー ねえ これが私でいいかな
Hi, maybe me... hey, is it okay if this is me?
いいでしょ そっと ちょっとじゃ 揺らがないの
It's fine, right? It won't waver easily or quickly
これくらいは ラッタラッタ 笑えちゃうの
This much, I can just laugh it off, rat-ta-rat-ta
笑えたら 次に行こう
If I can laugh, let's move on
気付いたら ちょっと成長してるよ
Before I knew it, I've grown a little bit
キュートにキュートに 甘いだけじゃなくて
Not just being cute, cute and sweet
ほんのりほんのり ほろ苦いの
But a little bit, a little bit bittersweet
だって合言葉 ピッと！して！マーマレード
Because the password is Pit-to! Shite! Marmalade
君に会えるまで 次は何にしよう
Until I can see you, what should I do next?
よっしゃ、ゲット、セット、レディ、ゴー！
Alright, get set, ready, go!
細部に凝って 真心込めて
Elaborating on details, with all my heart
届けたいんだもん
Because I want to deliver it
一期一会かもしれないけど
It might be a once-in-a-lifetime encounter, but
繋がる空みたく
Like the sky that connects us
どんな服を着て 街に出よう
What kind of clothes should I wear to go out?
どんな髪型を試そう
What kind of hairstyle should I try?
一つ一つ 君に見てほしいから
One by one, I want you to see them
本当だよ 君はどうだろう
It's true, how about you?
もしもがいっぱい いっぱい連なって
Many 'what ifs' lined up one after another
奇跡がいっぱい いっぱい起きちゃって
Many miracles happening one after another
見たことない 景色になる
Becoming a landscape never seen before
君と私が作った 景色だよ
It's the landscape that you and I made
とってもとっても 嬉しいんだ
I'm so, so happy
だからね 本当に本当にありがとうだ
So, really, really thank you
君がくれる その声 マーマレード
That voice you give me, Marmalade
どんな色にでもなれる
I can become any color
紅茶に溶かすメロディや
Like a melody dissolving in tea
食パンに塗るリズムで
With the rhythm of spreading it on bread
楽しさ 目が回るほど
The fun is enough to make my head spin
だから私は 私でいたい
That's why I want to be myself
こんなに こんなに 叶えたくて
This much, this much, I want to make it come true
強く願って 願うだけ 夢になって
Just by wishing, wishing strongly, it became a dream
なったからね 諦めるはずない
Since it did, there's no way I'll give up
そのステージは きっとそこにある
That stage is surely right there
一緒に一緒に 目指したいの
I want to aim for it together with you
景色を一緒に 一緒に作りたいの
I want to make the landscape together with you
仲間はしっかりと
Hold your friends close and firm,
ピッとしてマーマレード
Be sharp like marmalade!
私頑張るよ
I'll do my best!
頑張ってるからね
I'm working hard, you see!
よっしゃ get started!
Alright, let's get started!
ララララ...
La la la la...
ってな感じな歌ってこ
Sing along like that!
本当ありがとう
Thank you so much!
せーの、ハイ！
One, two, high!
ずっとねピッとしてマーマレード
Always be sharp like marmalade!
みんなと今日、7年目を一緒にお祝いすることができて、とっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy to be able to celebrate our 7th year together today!
これからも一生懸命頑張っていくので、みんな！これからも応援してくれますかー？
I'll keep working as hard as I can, so will you all continue to support me?
たくさんたくさん、素敵な思い出、作っていこうねー！！
Let's make lots and lots of wonderful memories together!!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
というわけで今の曲はピッとして！マーマレードでした。
So, that was "Pit to Shite! Marmalade".
パチパチありがとうございます。
Thank you for the applause.
本当に素敵なギターの演奏で歌うことができてとても嬉しいです。
I'm so happy I could sing to such wonderful guitar playing.
そして次の曲が、なんとギターとの1対1での、
And the next song is actually the last song
まあ曲はラストになるんですけども、
to be performed one-on-one with the guitar.
次の曲、「Chu-Chu-Lu」という曲を歌わせていただきます。
I will be singing the next song, "Chu-Chu-Lu".
なんとこの「Chu-Chu-Lu」っていう曲は、
Actually, for this song "Chu-Chu-Lu"...
アルバムのギターを村山遼さんがやってくださっています。
...Murayama Ryo-san played the guitar for the album version.
一緒に今日演奏することができてとても嬉しく思っています。
I'm very happy to be able to perform together today.
まさかね、アルバムの曲を弾いてくださった方と本当に一緒にセッションできるなんて思っていなかったのでとても幸せです。
I never thought I'd get to do a live session with the person who played on the album, so I'm very happy.
それでは最後の、ギターとの最後の曲お聞きください。「Chu-Chu-Lu」。
Now, please listen to the final song with the guitar. "Chu-Chu-Lu".
Chu-Chu-Lu Chu-Lu-Chu-Lu-Chu...
男の子はいつでも強がりな生き物の
Boys are always creatures who act tough,
弱さを嫌って涙は流さないの
hating weakness and refusing to shed tears.
傷つかない人などこの世にいないから
Since there's no one in this world who doesn't get hurt,
たまには本当の声を聞かせてよ
let me hear your real voice once in a while.
あなたはまだ不器用なフリです
You're still just pretending to be clumsy.
もういいよ 牙なんて捨てて
It's okay now, throw away those fangs.
深く深く愛してよ
Love me deeply, deeply.
酸いも甘いもメモリアル
Bittersweet memories.
恋は怖くないんだよ
Love isn't scary.
あなたなら大丈夫
You'll be just fine.
強く強くハグしてよ
Hug me tightly, tightly.
あの夜にサヨナラを
Say goodbye to that night.
いつもここで待ってるよ
I'll always be waiting here.
だからもっと
So please,
恐れずに愛してね
love me without fear.
せーの！
One, two!
Chu-Chu-Lu Chu-Lu-Chu-Lu-Chu...
誰もが一人だけじゃいられない生き物の
Everyone is a creature that cannot be alone,
弱さを認めない助けを求めない
Yet they won't admit weakness or ask for help.
出会うものよ
To the things I meet
私もまだ
I'm still a...
不器用なエンジェル
...clumsy angel
お願いよ
Please
翼を広げて
Spread your wings
高く高く 飛んでいくよ
Higher and higher, I'll fly
目指すのはサンクチュアリ
Aiming for the sanctuary
二人だけの 楽園で
In a paradise just for the two of us
甘い果実 かぶり
Taking a bite of sweet fruit
手と手 ぎゅっと つないでよ
Hold my hand tightly
じゃなきゃ 離れちゃうから
Or else we'll drift apart
ずっとここで一緒だよ
We'll be together here forever
だからもっと
So love me...
いつまでも 愛してね
...even more, forever
いつかできた 傷跡に
On the scars made someday
涙が 染みちゃうのなら
If tears sting them
笑顔のバンドエイドを あげるから
I'll give you a smiley-face Band-Aid
前を向いてさ 行こう
So look forward and let's go
深く深く 愛してよ
Love me deeply, deeply
何もかもが メモリアル
Everything is a memorial
恋は 怖くないでしょう
Love isn't scary, is it?
あなたと 私なら
If it's you and me
強く強く ハグしてよ
Hug me strongly, strongly
あの夜に さよなら
Goodbye to that night
いつもここで 待ってるよ
I'm always waiting here
だからもっと
So love me...
恐れずに 愛してね
...even more, without fear
せーの！
Ready, set!
Chu Chu Lu Chu Chu Chu Lu Chu Chu
Chu Chu Lu Chu Chu Chu Lu Chu
路地裏ライブ、ありがとうございました！
Thank you for the street live!
路地裏での練習もしっかりできたし
I was able to practice well on the street,
また次のステージでも歌っていきたいな
and I want to keep singing on the next stage too.
よっさん、また後で！
Yousa, see you later!
ライブやってます、よろしくお願いします。
I'm doing a live, please come!
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
皆さんライブやってるので、ぜひ見に来てください。
Everyone, I'm doing a live, so please come and see.
よろしくお願いします、よろしくお願いします。
Thank you, thank you.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
今ライブやってます、よろしくお願いします。
I'm doing a live now, please come!
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
これからライブをやるので、皆さん見に来ませんか？
I'm doing a live from now on, won't you all come see?
よろしくお願いします、よろしく…え、え？
Thank you, tha... oh, what?
すごいすごい、あ、
Wow, wow! Oh,
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
よろしくお願いします。すごい、こんな、
Thank you. Wow, I can't believe...
歌だけじゃなくて、ダンスの特訓する人もいるんだな。
...there's even someone doing dance training.
よろしくお願いします、よろしくお願いします。
Thank you, thank you.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
あ、この町はいろんな人がいるんだな。
Ah, there are all sorts of people in this town.
よろしくお願いします、よろしくお願いします。
Thank you, thank you.
よろしくお願いします。今度ライブやるんですけど、ぜひ見に来ませんか？
Thank you. I'm going to have a live soon, why not come see?
色々頑張ってるので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
I'm working hard on various things, so please come!
お願いします。あ、バイバイ！
Thank you. Oh, bye-bye!
ありがとうございました。見てくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you very much. Thank you for watching.
よろしくお願いします、よろしくお願いします。
Thank you, thank you.
うわっ、わっ、すごい！すごい！
Whoa! Wow, amazing! Amazing!
こんな町中で危なくないのかな？すごい、きれい。
Isn't it dangerous in the middle of town? Wow, beautiful.
きれいだなぁ。あ、よろしくお願いします。
It's so pretty. Oh, thank you.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
ライブやりませんか？よろしくお願いします。
Won't you come to the live? Thank you.
ライブやります、お願いします。
I'm doing a live, thank you.
Now Loading...
ライブやるんですけど
I'm holding a live show.
ぜひ見に来てくれませんか？
Would you please come and see it?
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
もし時間があったらぜひ見に来てくださいね！
If you have time, please do come and see it!
はい！というわけで
Right! So...
今度はこんな素敵なステージで歌うことができるようになりました！
Now, I'm able to sing on such a wonderful stage!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
そしてもうすでに素敵な音を奏でてくださっている
And already playing beautiful notes...
ピアノのウインクさんです！
...is Wink-san on the piano!
お願いします！
Thank you for having me!
よろしくお願いします！
Glad to have you here!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
そんなウインクさんと一緒に演奏する曲はこちらです
The song I'll be performing with Wink-san is this one.
ポラリスソラリス
Polaris Solaris
作詞・作曲：多田慎也
Lyrics & Composition: Shinya Tada
星の数だけほら
Look, as many as the stars
選択肢があったストーリー
There were choices in the story
君の描いた夢に
In the dream you drew
出会えた奇跡感じて
Feeling the miracle of meeting you
きっとあの空
Surely in that sky
七つの星輝いて
Seven stars are shining
輝いて
Shining
色んなことがあったよね
Many things happened, didn't they?
立ち止まることだって
Even the times we stopped
それに意味があるって
That they have a meaning
教えてくれたね
You taught me
ポラリス 旅をする者 いつも導いて
Polaris, always guide the travelers
私にとって
For me
それが君だって思うよ
I think that's you
ポラリス 変わらずにいてね いつも見守って
Polaris, please stay the same, always watching over
永遠を信じたいよ
I want to believe in eternity
物語
Story
神様がくれた
God gave me
運命っていう名のストーリー
A story called fate
離ればなれでも
Even if we're apart
一つの奇跡信じて
Believing in one miracle
高い空
High in the sky
五つの星きらめいて
Five stars twinkling
きらめいて
Twinkling
迷ってばかりの道だって
Even on a path full of hesitation
ずっとね 怖くなかった
I was never afraid
そばに君がいたから
Because you were by my side
勇気をくれたね
You gave me courage
ポラリス 道標のように そっと佇んで
Polaris, standing softly like a signpost
未来をちゃんと
To properly find...
見つけられたんだ ありがとう
...the future, thank you
ポラリス 素直になれるよ 君の言葉って
Polaris, your words make me honest
続きを描きたいよ
I want to draw the continuation
物語
Of the story
点と点を
Points and points
繋いで
Connecting
あのね あのね 君の
You know, you know, your...
その目を見ると明日を
When I look into those eyes...
信じたいと そう思えるの
...I feel like I can believe in tomorrow
でもね でもね 時は
But, but, time...
過ぎてしまうから
...will pass by
今を刻んで
Carve out the present
忘れないでいて ずっと
Please don't forget it, forever
ポラリス 旅をする者 いつも導いて
Polaris, always guide the travelers
私にとって
For me
それが君だって思うよ
I think that's you
ポラリス 変わらずにいてね いつも見守って
Polaris, please stay the same, always watching over
永遠を信じたいよ
I want to believe in eternity
物語
Story
ポラリス 道標のように そっと佇んで
Polaris, standing softly like a signpost
未来をちゃんと
To properly find...
見つけられたんだ ありがとう
...the future, thank you
ポラリス 素直になれるよ 君の言葉って
Polaris, your words make me honest
続きを描きたいよ
I want to draw the continuation
物語
Of the story
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
や、本日はえー、ここでのライブということで少し大人っぽく
So, for today's live here, I wanted to go for a bit of a more mature look,
そしてちょっとね、髪型もちょっと変えてきてみちゃいました。
and so, I've even changed up my hairstyle a little.
いかがだったでしょうか？
What do you think?
そして改めてご紹介します。
And I'd like to introduce him once again.
ピアノのWingsさんです。
On the piano, this is Wings-san.
や、もうとっても素敵な演奏で
Wow, such a wonderful performance...
あ、自分がすごいね、なんかときめいちゃってずっと聴いていたいっていう感じだったんですけど
I was actually so moved myself, I felt like I just wanted to keep listening forever,
私が歌わないとね、あの、ダメだなと思ってしっかり歌わせていただきました。
but I realized if I didn't sing, that wouldn't do, so I made sure to give it my all.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
そして次の歌も、私にとって思い出深い歌です。
And the next song is also a very memorable one for me.
それはコトバカゼという曲なんですけど
It's a song called "Kotobakaze",
私の初めて出したアルバムの中の曲でたくさん聴いていただいていた曲だと思います。
a song from my very first album that I think many of you have listened to a lot.
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen to it.
コトバカゼ。
Kotobakaze.
胸の奥がこそばゆい
A tickling feeling deep in my chest
コトバカゼ
作詞・作曲：多田慎也
Kotobakaze
Lyrics & Composition: Shinya Tada
本当ずるい人だなぁ
You really are a sly person
無邪気すぎるその笑顔
That smile of yours is far too innocent
友達だったのに
Even though we were just friends
金曜日の街ざわめく
The Friday town is buzzing
心も浮き足立って
My heart is also getting restless
今日ならば言えそうな
I feel like today is the day I could say it
気がしたい 気がする
I feel it... I really feel it
コトバカゼ ふわり 頬をかすめ
A word-breeze softly brushes my cheek
恋はこんな風に始まる
This is how love begins
どこか懐かしいでも知らない
Somewhere nostalgic, yet unknown
微かな匂い
A faint scent
冷たくしないでよねぇ
Don't be so cold to me, okay?
あなたの秘密も知りたい
I want to know your secrets too
誰より側で笑うよ
I'll be the one laughing by your side more than anyone
ふわり
Lightly
時に消えた物語
Stories that faded with time
私だけに話してね
Please tell them only to me
繋がり難い手を繋いで
Holding hands that were hard to connect
ちょっと気になってる
I'm starting to care a little bit
誕生日ももうすぐだって
Saying that my birthday is coming up soon
さりげなく伝えられた
You told me so casually
「好きだよ」と書いてみたディスプレイ
On the display where I wrote "I like you"
そのままで
Leaving it just like that
コトバカゼ ふわり 想い届け
A word-breeze, softly deliver my feelings
愛はきっとこんな風に知る
This must be how we learn about love
あの日少しだけ縮まった距離
The distance that closed just a little that day
信じていいの
Can I believe in it?
答えを聞かせてよねぇ
Let me hear your answer, okay?
あなたとの明日は来るの？
Will there be a tomorrow with you?
誰より側で涙はキラリ
By your side more than anyone, tears glisten
どんな昨日をあなたは生きてきたの
What kind of yesterdays have you lived through?
ねぇ
Hey
コトバカゼ ふわり
A word-breeze, softly
…涙 綺麗に
...and the tears are beautiful.
コトバカゼ ふわり 涙 光
Words like the wind, softly, tears and light.
コトバカゼ ふわり 頬かすめ
Words like the wind, softly grazing my cheek.
恋はこんなふうに始まる
This is how love begins.
どこか懐かしい でも知らない
Something nostalgic, yet unknown.
微かな匂い
A faint scent.
冷たくしないでよね ねえ
Don't be cold to me, okay?
あなたの秘密も知りたい
I want to know your secrets, too.
誰よりそばで笑うよ ふわり
I'll smile by your side more than anyone, softly.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
次の曲は、『好き、泣いちゃいそうだ』という曲になります。
The next song is called "Suki, Naichaishou da."
『好き、泣いちゃいそうだ』も、えーと、私の初めてのライブで最後に歌った曲で、
"Suki, Naichaishou da" was also, well, the last song I sang at my very first live,
みんなとの思い出がたくさん詰まった大事な曲です。
and it's a precious song filled with many memories with all of you.
それを今日、このアコースティックで歌わせていただきますので、
Since I'll be singing it today in this acoustic style,
ぜひぜひ聴いていただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy if you'd give it a listen.
それでは聴いてください。『好き、泣いちゃいそうだ』。
Now, please listen. "Suki, Naichaishou da."
みんなコメントありがとう。見えてるよ。
Everyone, thanks for the comments. I can see them.
好き、泣いちゃいそうだ
作詞：まつもとななみ 作曲：青木康平
Suki, Naichaishou da
Lyrics: Nanami Matsumoto / Composition: Kohei Aoki
意地悪な言葉を
Saying mean things
わざと言ったりして
on purpose to you
欲張りなくらい君を知りたいよ
I want to know everything about you, greedily so.
恥ずかしがらないで おいで
Don't be shy, come to me.
出会えた偶然を
This chance encounter,
運命に変えたいな
I want to turn it into destiny.
始まった恋は加速していくの
The love that's begun is accelerating.
ブレーキはかけられないの
And I can't pull the brakes.
未完成なパズル
An incomplete puzzle
恋というピースを
With the piece called love,
重ね合わせよう
let's put it together.
心は君で埋まってく
My heart is being filled with you.
いつだって そのままの君が好き
I always love you just the way you are.
不器用で人見知り
Clumsy and shy,
無口だけど誰より優しい人ね
quiet, but you're kinder than anyone.
少し猫背なとこも
The way you're slightly stooped,
優柔不断なとこも
the way you're indecisive,
強がるけど泣き虫なとこも 全部
and the way you're a crybaby despite acting tough—all of it.
好き、泣いちゃいそうなくらい
I love you so much, I could cry.
二つの影が寄り添う帰り道は なんだか少し切なくて
The two shadows cuddling on the way home, it's somehow a little sad.
風になびく髪が君を追いかける
My hair fluttering in the wind chases after you.
あと数センチの距離が 胸を締め付けるんだ
Those last few centimeters of distance squeeze my heart.
いつだって届きそうで届かない
It always feels within reach but I can't reach it.
触れそうで触れられない
It feels like I can touch it but I can't.
近そうで遠い君のその指先
Your fingertips that seem so close yet so far.
溢れ出すこの想い 今君に伝えたら
If I told you about these overflowing feelings now,
この手をギュッと握ってくれませんか
would you hold this hand tightly?
初めて出会った瞬間に胸が熱くなって
The moment we first met, my heart grew hot.
きっとあの日から君のこと
Surely since that day, I've...
また一緒にいたくて ずっと側にいたくて
...wanted to be with you again, wanted to be by your side forever.
君も同じ気持ちでいてくれるのかな
I wonder if you feel the same way too.
胸の痛みはきっと 好きの合図なんだね
The pain in my chest must be a sign of love.
痛くて苦しくて こんなにも温かい
It's painful and agonizing, yet so warm.
好き、泣いちゃいそうだ
I love you, I feel like I'm going to cry.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
見えてるよ。ありがとうございます。
I can see you. Thank you very much.
さあ、路地、そして、この素敵な場所ときて...
Now, from the back alley, to this wonderful place...
今、私の夢はアイドルなので
Right now, my dream is to be an idol,
いつかステージで歌いたいと思っています。
so I hope to sing on stage someday.
次も、来てくれるかな？
Will you come next time too?
あのステージでみんな、会おうね！
Let's all meet on that stage!
ミングさん、ありがとうございました！
Mingu-san, thank you very much!
そして、みんな、あとでね！
And everyone, see you later!
こんにちは。さっきは見てくれてありがとうございました。
Hello. Thank you for watching earlier.
落ち着いて見れましたか？
Were you able to watch comfortably?
ああ、よかった。
Ah, good.
ところで、私なんか見覚えがあるなと思ってるんですけど
By the way, I feel like I've seen you somewhere before.
この前街で、なんか側転とかバレエとか練習してたりしませんでしたか？
Weren't you practicing cartwheels or ballet in town the other day?
あ、やっぱしてましたよね。
Ah, you were, weren't you?
私あそこの時にビラ配ってて
I was handing out flyers there at the time,
いや、私もね、実はダンスとかをちょっと練習してるんですよ。
well, actually, I'm practicing dancing a little too.
あそこまで、そう、バレエとかはできないんですけど。
I can't do ballet or anything like that, though.
もしよかったら、一緒に練習してみたりしませんか？
If you'd like, would you like to try practicing together?
あ、いいですか？
Ah, really?
もしよければこれからずっと一緒に頑張っていきましょう！
If it's okay, let's keep working hard together from now on!
ああ、嬉しい！
Ah, I'm so happy!
じゃ、これからじゃ、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Well then, I look forward to working with you!
一緒に頑張ろう！
Let's do our best together!
おー！ よろしくね！
Oh! Nice to meet you!
今度ライブやります。よろしくお願いします！
I'm doing a live show soon. Please come!
ライブいかがですか？よろしくお願いします。
How about a live show? Please come.
よろしくお願いします。
Please check it out.
ライブやります！
I'm having a live show!
よろしくお願いします！
Please take one!
こんにちは、ライブやります。
よろしくお願いします！
Hello, I'm holding a live show.
Please take one!
よろしくお願いします！
こんにちは、ライブやります。
Hello, I'm holding a live show.
よろしくお願いします！
Please take one!
こんにちは。
Hello there.
ライブいかがですか？
How about a live show?
よろしくお願いします！
Please take one!
こんにちは、今度ライブをやるんですけど...
Hello, I'm having a live show soon...
...いかがですか？
...would you like to come?
あん肝も一緒にビラを配ってくれてます。
Ankimo is helping me hand out flyers too.
絶対素敵なライブにするので...
I'll make it a wonderful show, so...
...ぜひ見に来てくれませんか？
...won't you please come and see it?
あっ、見に来てくれますか？
Ah, you'll come and see it?
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
やったね！やったね！やったね！
We did it! We did it! We did it!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future as you
あの夢手にしたい
I want to reach that dream
それぞれ違った心で
With our hearts, each beating differently
走れ　Go!
Run, Go!
Shiny Smily Story
せーの、ホロライブ！
Ready, Hololive!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えた
It sprouted in a place where everything was pitch black
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳を奪われた
A tiny bit of hope captured my eyes
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart that wavers with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was squeezing out every bit of my tiny courage
「諦める」の文字　デリートして進む
Deleting the word 'give up' and moving forward
苦しい時も　もう私は一人じゃないから
Even in painful times, I'm not alone anymore
だからもっと夢を追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
それぞれ超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you the worlds we'll each transcend
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try to access it
後悔なんてさせない
I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った心で
With our hearts, each beating differently
走れ　Go!
Run, Go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
Dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
Will deliver a light you've never seen to reality
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here
また新しい光を捜したくなるよ
I'll want to search for a new light again
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile as I move forward
悲しい時に見返すよ　力が湧くから
I'll look back at it when I'm sad, it gives me strength
胸を張って夢を追いかけたい
I want to puff out my chest and chase my dreams
奇跡のストーリー
A story of miracles
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create a never-ending dream together
誰一人欠かせない
Not a single person is replaceable
愛が舞ったこの世界
In this world where love fluttered
それぞれ違った心で
With our hearts, each beating differently
彩れ
Let's color it
みんなー！ありがとうー！
歌うことができたよー！
Everyone! Thank you!
I was able to sing!
...だー！
...!
悲しい時も 寂しい時も
Even when sad, even when lonely
信じ合えるものがある
There's something we can believe in together
忘れずに この鼓動 鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep this heartbeat sounding, without forgetting
終わらない世界に 溢れ出すよ
Overflowing into an endless world
笑顔たち
Smiles
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes crying, wanting to laugh together again
同じ未来見たい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩
Let's take a step towards a miracle
息切らして 追いかけたい
I want to chase it until I'm out of breath
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像超えてく 世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that exceeds your imagination
アクセスしてみない？
Won't you try accessing it?
ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
後悔なんてここにない
There's no such thing as regret here
それぞれ違った心で 作る輪
A circle created by each of our different hearts
はい！というわけで、ついにアリーナで歌いましたー！
Yes! And so, I finally sang at the arena!
イエーイ！わぁ、すごい！わぁーーー！
Yay! Wow, amazing! Waaaaah!
そして先程一緒に演奏してくださった
And also, those who just performed with me
りょうさんとウィンクさんと、そしてあん肝も一緒です！イエーイ！
Ryo-san and Wink-san, and Ankimomo is here too! Yay!
というわけで、ここからは4人で歌を歌っていきたいなと思っております
So, from here on, I'd like for the four of us to sing together
ありがとうございます。いやもう、こんなに豪華な感じで歌わせていただけるなんて本当に幸せです
Thank you. I'm so happy to be able to sing in such a luxurious setting
みんなも生の演奏を楽しんでくれてるかな？
Is everyone enjoying the live performance?
次の曲も、全体曲から選びました
I chose the next song from the group songs too
自分の中では一番難しい曲で
For me, it's the most difficult song
とってもなんか練習した曲でもあるので、温かく見てもらえたら嬉しいです
It's also a song I practiced a lot, so I'd be happy if you'd watch warmly
次の曲聴いてください。Prism Melody
Please listen to the next song: Prism Melody
そうさずっと
That's right, forever
僕らの奇跡が
Our miracle
途切れないように歌うんだ
We sing so it never breaks
もっと高く大きな声で
Higher and with a louder voice
ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
聞こえてた 何かが始まるサイン
I could hear it, the sign that something is starting
集まって 気づけば鼓動奏でた
Gathered together, before I knew it, our heartbeats played a melody
夢見るだけじゃ 物足りないでしょう？
Just dreaming isn't enough, is it?
君を待ってる world があるよ
There's a world waiting for you
楽しい予感にほら
Look, in this happy premonition
伸びのびを目一杯
To our heart's content
ときめきは止められないから走ろう
Because the excitement can't be stopped, let's run
連れて行くよ 光の真ん中
I'll take you there, to the middle of the light
夢の先へ羽ばたける
We can fly beyond our dreams
勇気は君の願い
Courage is your wish
みんなで繋いだこの奇跡が
This miracle we all connected together
途切れないように歌うんだ
We sing so it never breaks
もっと高く大きな声で
Higher and with a louder voice
ハイ！
Hai!
答えとか理屈に 惑わされて
Bewildered by answers and logic
彷徨っても 戻って来れる場所があったんだ
Even if we wander, there was a place we could return to
地図にない道行く 僕らの旅
Our journey on a path not on any map
願いだけが道標だよ
Only our wishes are our guidepost
夢の色が変わっても 変わらないメロディ
Even if the color of the dream changes, the melody remains the same
君のために 僕らのために 歌おう
Let's sing for you, for us
そうさきっと 僕らの奇跡は
That's right, surely our miracle
終わらないよう 涙さえきっかけに変えて行こう
To make sure it never ends, let's turn even our tears into a catalyst
信じていて
Believe in it
あん肝と一緒に
With Ankimo
どこへだって飛び出していこう
Let's fly away anywhere
もっと遠く
Even further
空を越えて
Beyond the sky
ギター！楢原遼太！
Guitar! Ryota Narahara!
ピアノ！ウィング！
Piano! Wing!
未来の僕らに
To our future selves
まだ見ぬ君に
To you, whom I've yet to see
伝えたいこと たくさんあるんだ
There are so many things I want to tell you
迎えたい今は
The 'now' I want to face
当たり前なんかじゃない
Is not something to be taken for granted
翼を広げ さあ今 運ぼう
Spread your wings, and let's carry them now
Take my hand
連れていくよ
I'll take you there
光の真ん中
To the center of the light
夢の先へ
Beyond the dream
羽ばたける
We can soar
勇気は君の願い
Courage is your wish
みんなで繋いだこの奇跡が
This miracle we all connected
途切れないように歌うんだ
I'll sing so it never breaks
もっと高く
Even higher
大きな声で
With a loud voice
僕らの未来 彩って
Color our future
どこまでも響け Prism Melody
Resonate everywhere, Prism Melody
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
はい！ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you very much!
こちら「Prism Melody」でしたー！
That was "Prism Melody"!
そして、ここで！
And now, here!
アリーナに来て、お知らせがあります！
Coming to the arena, I have an announcement!
わーい！
Yay!
おー、ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
ふふっ、ありがとうございます。
Hehe, thank you.
というわけで、そのお知らせがこちらです！
So, here is the announcement!
おっおっ、BGMすごい！ありがとうございます。
Oh, the BGM is amazing! Thank you.
ときのそら活動６周年記念、え、グッズが出ます！
Tokino Sora Activity 6th Anniversary, uh, goods will be released!
こちらのグッズなんですが、まず、そうですね、
Regarding these goods, first, let's see,
いろんなセットがあるんですが、１つずつ見ていこうと思います！
there are various sets, but I'd like to look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！「そらと一緒に抱き枕カバー」
First, this! "Dakimakura Cover Together with Sora"
ということで、おるだん先生描き下ろしのものになっております。
It features a new illustration by Ordan-sensei.
表も裏も、全然ね、ちょっと違う感じなんですけど、
The front and back are quite different,
どちらも可愛いので、ぜひぜひ見てもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
but both are cute, so I'd be happy if you'd take a look.
いつでも私と一緒に過ごしてね！
Spend time with me anytime!
そして、次がこちら！
And next is this!
「あんきもスリッパ」です！
It's "Ankimo Slippers"!
今回は、「お部屋で私と一緒に」みたいなテーマで作らせていただきました。
This time, we made them with a theme like "together with me in your room".
私とお揃いの抱き枕、そしてあんきものスリッパを履いて、
With the same dakimakura as me, and wearing the Ankimo slippers,
いつでも私みたいになってみない？ということで、
why not try being like me all the time? So,
とってもね、あの、履き心地もいいものになってるので、よろしくお願いします！
they are very, well, comfortable to wear, so please check them out!
そして、こちら！記念ボイス！
And here! Anniversary Voice!
シチュエーションボイス「君と一緒に過ごす休みの日」
Situation Voice "A Day Off Spent with You"
休みの日、みんなでどうやって過ごそうかなって考えながらシチュエーションボイス撮らせてもらいました。
I recorded this situation voice while thinking about how we would all spend a day off.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
そして、最後にこちら！
And finally, this!
「活動６周年記念フルセット」ということで、
The "Activity 6th Anniversary Full Set",
箔押し複製サインとメッセージが付いたものと、
which includes a foil-stamped replica signature and message,
おるだん先生描き下ろしのポストカード、そして特典ボイス「君と一緒にお昼寝」というですね、
a postcard illustrated by Ordan-sensei, and a bonus voice called "Napping with You",
もう１つのシチュエーションボイスも付いてきます。
another situation voice is also included.
箔押しではありますが、心を込めてメッセージ書かせていただいたので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
Although it's foil-stamped, I wrote the message with all my heart, so please do check it out.
そしてそして、まだまだあります！
And, and, there's more!
そしてなんと！公式ファンクラブの方のですね、アプリができまして！
And surprise! An app for the official fan club has been created!
無料登録もあるので、ぜひぜひ見てもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
There's also a free registration, so I'd be happy if you could check it out.
たまに無料でブログとか書いたりしてます。
I sometimes write blogs for free.
「この人すごいブログ書くな」と思われてるかもしれませんが、あの３日に１回とかよく書いてます。
You might think, "This person writes a lot of blogs," but I often write them about once every three days.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
そして、最後に！
And finally!
お知らせ、言ってなかったお知らせがあります！こちらです！
An announcement, an announcement I haven't mentioned yet! Here it is!
そのファンクラブでですね、本日２３時にリハーサルの映像がアップされます！
On that fan club, at 23:00 today, a video of the rehearsal will be uploaded!
途中までは無料で見ることができまして、
You can watch it for free up to a certain point,
途中からは有料にはなるんですけども、
and from there it will be paid content,
ぜひぜひ、あのリハーサルの映像見たいなっていう人、
but if you really want to see the rehearsal footage,
「配信」となってるんですが、まあプレミア公開的な感じかな？で見れると思いますので、
it says "distribution," but I think it'll be like a premiere? You can watch it at,
２３時、ぜひ良ければ来てください。
23:00, so please come if you'd like.
そして、この後なんですが、
And after this,
メンバーシップ限定で、アフターライブ的なことをやっちゃうと思いますので、
I'll be doing something like an after-live exclusively for members,
まだまだ歌えますので、よろしくお願いします！
so I can still sing more, please look forward to it!
それでは、コメントが見えなくなってしまいましたが、
Well then, I can't see the comments anymore,
みんな、喜んでくれてるかな？
but is everyone enjoying themselves?
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
えー、次で、最後の曲になります。
Um, the next one will be the last song.
本当に本当に、最後の曲です。
Truly, truly, the last song.
えー、最後の曲も、やっぱり全楽曲の中から、
Um, for the last song, as expected,
選ばせていただきました。
I chose from all of my songs.
みんなで、パレードをして、
We want to end it with a parade together,
終わっていきたいよね？
right?
ということで、最後の曲はこちらにしたいと思います。
So, I'd like this to be the last song.
みんなのコメント、見えてるよ！
I can see everyone's comments!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
「Our Bright Parade」
"Our Bright Parade"
パレパレパレ
Pare, pare, pare,
輝くんだよ
it's shining
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal
パレパレパレ
Pare, pare, pare,
探しに行く
let's go find it
スタートは何処だって
No matter where the start is
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
Our Bright Parade
作詞・作曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics & Composition: Shota Horie
ただ 独り言 綴った
I just composed a soliloquy
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I just ran because I wanted to start
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Lit up in the distant darkness
それは 眩しすぎた名前
It was a name that was too bright
それは 優しすぎる思い出
It was a memory that was too kind
もっと 近づこうと手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer
思いがけず結びあった
Unexpectedly, we were tied together
ほら 今 迷子は僕らになった
Look, now we've become lost children
パレパレパレ
Pare, pare, pare,
輝くんだよ
it's shining
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Bring both frustration and affection
風 夢 羽 飛び立ってさ
Wind, dreams, wings, take flight
ささやかな祈り 射光
A humble prayer, rays of light,
終わりなき日差し
endless sunshine
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of finding you
ここから これから
From here, from now on,
Our Bright Parade
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
まだ 頼りない予感を
A still unreliable premonition
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing, there's nothing to be ashamed of
誰も解けないイマジナリー
An imaginary that no one can solve
いつか また会えるおまじない
A spell to meet again someday
あの日 ゼロに始まったストーリー
The story that started at zero that day
数え切れない言の葉
Countless words
なぞるような想いじゃないさ
It's not a feeling like tracing
ほら 今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us one
パレパレパレ
Pare, pare, pare,
美しいんだよ
it's beautiful
許し合える刹那 夜は煌めく
The moment we can forgive each other, the night sparkles
雨 晴れ 糧 また笑い空
Rain, clear skies, nourishment, and a laughing sky again
ふさわしい旅路とは君と歩くことさ
A worthy journey is walking with you
君と歩くことなんだ
It's walking with you
ただいまを聞けば おかえりと叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't it obvious?
パレパレパレ
Pare, pare, pare,
輝くんだよ
it's shining
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
What fills the darkness is you, it's me
パレパレパレ
Pare, pare, pare,
輝くんだよ
it's shining
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Bring both frustration and affection
風 夢 羽 飛び立ってさ
Wind, dreams, wings, take flight
ささやかな祈り 射光
A humble prayer, rays of light,
終わりなき日差し
endless sunshine
君と飛び込んでいく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in with you, it's a wonderful start
もっと彼方 これからも
Further beyond, from now on too
Our Bright Parade Parade
本当に本当に、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so, so much!
せーの！
One, two!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
このあとは、アフターパーティーで
After this, at the after-party...
会おうねー！
...let's meet up!